So, external indices are all good and well,
外部指标都很不错
but they require that we have labels for our datasets.
但它要求我们的数据集有标签
Most of the time, however,
但很多时候
we're going to be working on datasets that are not labeled,
我们的数据集并没有标签
specifically, when we were talking about unsupervised learning.
更具体点 就是在非监督学习的情况下
And so, this is the case where internal indices are a lot more useful for us.
我们要借助于内部指标
These are a few examples of internal indices,
这些是内部指标的一些示例
and a couple of them are available in scikit-learn.
其中一些在 scikit-learn 中也有用到
We'll look at silhouette index a little bit more closely.
我们进一步来看轮廓系数
It gives a score between minus one and one to any clustering that we do.
它会给任何一个聚类在 -1 到 1 之间的值评分
So, let's take an example here.
我们看个例子
Let's say we have a dataset and we run it through
假如这是我们的数据集 我们对其进行聚类算法
a clustering algorithm and we get this result.
然后得到这个结果
So, this dataset is not labeled,
这个数据集是没有标签的
so we cannot compare against an original ground truth or original labeling.
所以我们不能与原始真相或原始标签进行比较
So, all we have to do, all we can do is do
我们必须要做并且能做的是
an internal index and score it using something like silhouette coefficient.
借助内部指标并利用轮廓系数对其进行评分
So, calculating the silhouette coefficient goes like this,
所以 计算轮廓系数的过程是这样
there's a silhouette coefficient for each point,
每个点有一个轮廓系数
each sample in the dataset,
对于数据集中的每个样本
we can calculate a silhouette coefficient.
我们都可以计算轮廓系数
And that is basically, b minus a,
计算公式为 b-a
over whichever one is larger,
除以 a 和 b 中较大的一个
either a or b. So, what is a?
所以 a 表示什么呢
A, is the average distance to other samples in the same cluster.
a 是同一个聚类中到其它样本的平均距离
Let's take an example, this point here.
我们以这个点为例
Let's try to calculate the silhouette coefficient for this point.
来计算这个点的轮廓系数
A, for it is the average distance to other samples in the cluster,
由于 a 是同一个聚类中到其它样本的平均距离
so it's the average of these two distances.
所以它等于这两个距离的平均值
Okay, and that's a. What about b?
这就是 a 那么 b 又是什么呢
B, is the average distance to samples in the closest neighboring cluster.
b 是与它距离最近不同聚类中到样本的平均距离
And so, to do that, we have to calculate the distance
所以要得到 b 我们必须计算这个点
between this point and every other cluster.
到其它各个聚类中点的距离
So, the distance between the point and
这个点到这个橘黄色的聚类之间的距离
this orange cluster is the average of these two distances,
就是这个点到这两个橘黄色点距离的平均值
and then the distance between it and green is the average between these two,
这个点到绿色聚类的距离就是这个点到这两个绿色点之间距离的平均值
and so we can compare those and decide that okay, yes.
我们进行比较可知
This is the closest neighboring cluster.
这个绿色聚类位于这个点距离最近的聚类
So b is the average of these two distances.
所以 b 等于这个点到这两个绿色点距离的平均值
We plug them in and we get a silhouette coefficient for the point.
我们将 a、b 代入得到该点的轮廓系数
We do this with every point in the clustering and
我们计算聚类中每个点的轮廓系数
then we average those and we get a silhouette coefficient for the entire clustering.
然后取其平均值 就得到了整个聚类的轮廓系数
Let's look at an example of silhouette coefficient and have it
我们来看一个轮廓系数的例子
help us find the best number of clusters to cluster a dataset.
让它帮助我们找到聚类数据集的中聚类的最佳数量
So finding k. So let's say we have this original,
要算得 K 假如我们有这个
this dataset that is unlabeled.
原始的 没有标签的数据集
If we run k-means on k equals two,
如果我们进行 K 均值聚类且 K=2
we get this result,
结果如下
and it gets this score.
得到评分为
So, 0.798.
0.798
If we run K-means with k equals three,
如果我们进行 K 均值聚类且 K=3
we get this result,
结果如下
and yay, it has a higher silhouette score.
得到的轮廓得分更高
So, this matches our intuition a lot better.
这更加符合我们的直觉
What about k equals four?
如果 K=4 呢？
We're really hoping that silhouette score for four would be lower than three,
我们希望 K=4 的轮廓得分比 K=3 的低
and it turns out to be much lower.
结果确实如此
So this is 0.641.
其得分为 0.641
And so from these three,
所以在这三个 K 值中
silhouette's coefficient tells us that k equals three is the right choice.
轮廓系数告诉我们 K=3 是最正确的选择
And this is very reassuring for us because we now have a mathematical formula that
这对我们来说是个好消息
can validate our intuition of how many clusters appear in this datasets,
我们现在可以通过数学公式来验证对数据集中聚类数量的猜测了
and that's something we can do if we have multiple dimensions that we cannot
如果有多个我们无法想象并直观分裂的维度
visualize and then intuitively split like this.
我们就可以这样做
k equals five, much worse score, 0.491.
K=5 时的评分结果更糟糕 为 0.491
And silhouette coefficient is penalizing k
当 K=4 或 K=5 时
equals four and k equals five because a clustering like this,
轮廓系数在进行罚分 因为在这样的聚类中
there's not enough of a distance between these two clusters.
这两个聚类之间的距离不够
So that gets it a penalty and the lower score.
所以其结果为罚分 得分更低
So, this is an example where we tried to look at four values of k,
所以 在这个例子中 我们试着为 K 赋了四个值
we can do that with a lot more values of k. So,
我们还可以为其赋更多的值
this is a graph where we see values of k between 2 and 100.
所以 这张图表显示的是 K 在 2 到 100 之间的得分
And we can see that no matter how many more clusters we break the dataset into,
我们可以看到 无论我们将数据集分割成多少个类
k equals three is the highest scoring silhouette score.
K=3 时的轮廓得分最高
Another example we can look at is this dataset where
我们再来看一个例子
we can clearly see that values of two or three are probably
我们能很明显的发现 K=2 或 3
the best values of k for
是这个数据集最好的 K 值
this dataset and then no matter how much we increase the number of clusters,
不管我们再如何增大聚类的数量
it never gets a score that's quite as good or high-scoring as two or three.
轮廓得分都没有 K=2 或 3 时的好
We can also use silhouette coefficient to compare clustering
我们也可以利用轮廓系数来比较聚类算法
algorithms and how they did on a certain dataset.
比较它们对一个特定数据集的效果
So, this is an example where we have,
来看这个例子
we are on K-means we got 0.801,
我们进行 K 均值聚类 得分为 0.801
Single Link gets the exact same result, same score,
单连接算法的得分也一样
Complete Link does the same, Ward,
全连接算法 Ward 最小方差法 DBSCAN
DBSCAN, all of them get the same score for doing the same job.
其结果和得分都一样
But let's look at this dataset here.
但我们来看看这个数据集
So K-means gets 0.637,
进行 K 均值聚类 其得分为 0.637
which seems okay, but let's see what Single Link does.
看起来还可以 但我们来看看单连接算法
It gets a score very close to zero because
其得分接近于 0
one cluster ate up almost the entire dataset. So, this is good.
一个聚类几乎占完了整个数据集 还不错
This is reassuring for us.
我们可以放心了
Complete Link gets a an okay score,
全连接算法也还不错
Ward does even better, DBSCAN.
Ward 最小方差法得分更好 DBSCAN...
So this example starts to show us how silhouette coefficient
所以这个例子告诉我们
is not the index that we'll use,
当我们使用 DBSCAN 时
that we should be using when you use DBSCAN.
我们不应该使用轮廓系数
Specifically because it doesn't have the concept of noise,
更具体的说 它没有噪音的概念
and then DBSCAN does not always tend to have
而 DBSCAN 并不总是倾向于
these compact clusters that
这些紧凑的聚类
silhouette coefficient rewards a clustering algorithm for resulting.
这些聚类可以通过轮廓系数奖励聚类算法来获得结果
And we can see something similar with the GMM,
我们可以发现与 GMM 类似的东西
which I think is a very elegant way to break down these.
我认为这是一种很优美的分割方式
I guess maybe the fourth-best score,
尽管这是第四好的得分
but I really love what it did there.
但是我非常喜欢这种分割
This final example shows a little bit of a downside of silhouette coefficient.
最后一个例子显示了轮廓系数的一些缺点
So, if we want to do
如果我们想
the two rings datasets and compare with different clustering algorithms,
使用两个环形的数据集 并与不同的聚类算法进行比较
K-means we get 0.35, Single Link however,
我们对其进行 K 均值聚类 得分为 0.35
gets them and carves them out perfectly,
但 Single Link 将其完美地分割 结果如下
but it gets a lower score than K-means.
但其得分比 K 均值的低
This is because silhouette coefficient is not built to
这是因为轮廓系数并不会奖励这样地分割数据集
reward carving out datasets like this or clusters like this.
或者这样的聚类
It wants to find those compact, dense,
它想找到从其它类分割开的
circular clusters that are well-separated from others.
那些紧凑 密集的环形类
And so, it doesn't really work well if this is the shape of
所以 如果你的数据外形或你想分割成的聚类外形是这样的
your dataset or these are the clusters that you want to carve out.
使用轮廓系数的效果并不是很好
Complete Link gets a better score even though it's a worse clustering,
尽管全连接的聚类很糟糕 但其得分稍好一点
Ward the same, DBSCAN does it perfectly,
Ward 也是这样 DBSCAN 分割得很完美
just beautifully and gets a score very close to zero.
分割得非常漂亮 得分接近于 0
It's another example of why we shouldn't use
这又是另一个证明我们处理 DBSCAN 时
silhouette coefficient when we're dealing with DBSCAN.
不应使用轮廓系数的例子
GMM is very close to K-means and very close score.
GMM 和 K 均值的得分很相近
So, for DBSCAN, we should never use silhouette coefficient.
所以处理 DBSCAN 时 不要使用轮廓系数
There is another algorithm however,
但还有另一个算法
and we have the paper linked below,
在下面链接的论文里
it's a internal index for density-based cluster validation,
介绍了基于密度的聚类评价的内部指标
that's actually it's named, DBCV,
其名为 DBCV 即 density-based clustering validation
density-based clustering validation, that is much better for something like DBSCAN.
它在处理 DBSCAN 时的效果更好